CJ WILLIAMS

UX/UI DESIGNER, MARKETER, FRONT-END DEVELOPER



Phone

406.579.1985

Email

cj@silencekillsdesign.com



Website

hirecj.netlify.com

SOCIAL



LinkedIn

/cjwilliamsworks



GitHub

/silencekillsdesign



Codepen

/silencekillsdesign

EDUCATION

Treehouse Academy

Front-End Development Techdegree teamtreehouse.com
2014 - 2022

Montana State University

Graphic Design & Music Technology Bozeman, MT 2003 - 2008

SKILLS

- UX / UI DESIGN
- HTML / CSS / JS / VUE / NUXT
- FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT
- ADOBE CREATIVE CLOUD
- MICROSOFT OFFICE
- SEMRUSH
- TECHNICAL SEO / SEM / PPC
- WORDPRESS / WOOCOMMERCE

CERTIFICATIONS

- GOOGLE ANALYTICS
- ADVANCED GOOGLE ANALYTICS
- HUBSPOT INBOUND
- MOZ SEO TRAINING
- CERTIFIED NUXT MASTER

PROFILE

Hey! Im CJ, a Marketing/E-Commerce Director, UX Systems Designer, and Front-End Web Developer with 10 years of management experience. Accountable leader who grinds in the trenches with the team. Data-driven decision maker, striving to optimize. Self-aware and an open-minded jokester strapped with bad dad jokes and a big heart. Looking to join a team with shared goals, values, and ethics so we can make awesome things even more awesome.

EXPERIENCE

Greenridge Farm

Digital Marketing and E-Commerce Manager / 2021 - 2023

- Improved organic and technical SEO, increasing web traffic over 96%
- Led targeted strategy to increase year-over-year online sales by 380%
- 700k impressions and 5.5k clicks on Ads with a a quarterly budget of \$3.2k
- New brand identity creation and implementation across all media and packaging
- Architechture, UX, website development and content curation for new website
- Management of Google suite, including Ads, Merchant Center, Tag Manager, Search, and Analytics

Hoists.com (and sister companies: Sievert Electric, Sievert Crane, and CES)

Marketing and E-Commerce Director / 2021 - 2023

- · Architect of a product catalog for multiple brands and product configurations
- Lead all UX practices, decisions, and implementation
- · Lead web development across all entities
- Technical SEO, SEM, SMM, and PPC strategy, management, and reporting
- · Lead infrastructure development for Dev, UX, Customer & Sales Support
- · Audio / Video / Digital asset production
- Launched to a reach of 14k unique visitors over its first two quarters, with 18k clicks, 1.8M impressions on a \$2k/mo. budget

SilenceKillsDesign

Agency Owner - UX, Development, Marketing, and Branding / 2007 - 2020

- UX Research and Development for small- and medium-sized B2B clientele
- · Management of multiple clients' online presence and identity
- SaaS admin interface design for web apps for integration with Oracle
- Brand asset design for digital and print mediums
- Website and e-commerce architecture, development, design, and optimization
- Owned SEO / SEM / PPC / SMM strategies, tracking, and reporting
- Track and report on KPI and goal completion

Xtant Medical

Digital Marketing Manager / 2012 - 2016

- · Design and Development of public-facing site
- Design and Development of investor and internal sales portal
- · SEO, SEM, PPC, SMM, Ad Buying
- · Brand design, management, and development